<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Whitepapers on Themelio knowledge base</title>
    <link>https://docs.themelio.org/whitepapers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Whitepapers on Themelio knowledge base</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2020 Themelio Labs (https://themelio.org/)</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://docs.themelio.org/whitepapers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Themelio: a stable blockchain for an unstable world</title>
      <link>https://docs.themelio.org/whitepapers/themelio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.themelio.org/whitepapers/themelio/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Themelio is a decentralized, public blockchain designed to support a new blockchain paradigm, where the blockchain is used as a low-level, stable, and simple root of trust rather than an application or full-featured application platform. We present evidence that this new paradigm is crucial for blockchains to fully realize their key feature of endogenous trust, or trust generated not through preexisting trust in protocol participants but through internal cryptoeconomic mechanisms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Synkletos: Themelio&#39;s collusion-resistant consensus mechanism</title>
      <link>https://docs.themelio.org/whitepapers/synkletos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.themelio.org/whitepapers/synkletos/</guid>
      <description>Abstract In this whitepaper, we discuss Synkletos, the core cryptoeconomic mechanism that powers Themelio&amp;rsquo;s proof-of-stake consensus. Consensus algorithms used to secure public blockchains differ significantly in their design constraints from those driving traditional fault-tolerant distributed systems. This is because blockchains must rigorously model trust within a game-theoretical model, rather than simply making assumptions about fault tolerance. To truly achieve incentive-compatible security, we cannot rely on the typical approach of considering ideal honest behavior and then positing an adversary with certain powers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Melmint: trustless stable cryptocurrency</title>
      <link>https://docs.themelio.org/whitepapers/melmint/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.themelio.org/whitepapers/melmint/</guid>
      <description>Note: this is a minimally revised version of a paper we published at CryptoEconSys 2020
Decentralized cryptocurrencies have gathered increasing interest in the past few years, raising hopes of a new era of non-sovereign electronic money. Unfortunately, cryptocurrencies perform poorly as actual money due to their unacceptably volatile purchasing power. &amp;ldquo;Stablecoins&amp;rdquo; aiming to reduce this volatility, on the other hand, tend to peg to an external currency like the US dollar, gravely weakening the decentralization that makes cryptocurrencies so attractive.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
